# FRANCISCO OLIVARES









COMPUTER SECURITY TECHNICIAN NETWORK SYSTEMS TECHNICIAN SYSADMIN

I've been using Linux as my main OS for 5 years, I started using Ubuntu, Debian and derivatives. Then Fedora (Red Hat community version) and currently I use Arch Linux and SUSE on work.

I'm always expanding my knowledge in everything related to computing, especially in Linux systems, administration and servers.

#### **EXPERIENCIA LABORAL**

### SysAdmin

New Media Professional Services

Febrero 2023 - actualidad

- ZENworks, software deployment, regedit settings, powershell scripting, GPOs, DLUs.
- OES, **SLES**, eDirectory (**LDAP**). Updates and upgrades of production servers.
- VMware, ESXi, server deployment planning and upgrades.
- Scripts, shell, powershell, bat. USMT
- N1 and N2 user and customer support
- Definition of strategies to be followed and their development.
- Filr, AAuth, 2FA, dns, dhcp, linux services. Documentation for customers.

#### IT Technician

Unitel - Sistemas de Telecomunicaciones

September 2022 - January 2023

- IT support for customers and users of N1, N2
- Switches, APs, routers Aruba y Cisco,
- Office 365 control panel managment
- · Citrix, VMware. Incident resolution, tickets.

#### SysAdmin

**Poultry Company** 

April 2019 - January 2022 (2 years, 8 months)

- Linux Server, vsftpd, top, htop, netdata, duplicity, ufw, motion, ethtool, samba, ostickets
- Windows client-server applications.
- IT Support N1 and N2
- Definition of strategies to be followed and their development.
- Control of the results of the actions.
- Windows Desktop + Server 2012 Applications and Users
- **Linux** Server **Backups** LVM, Duplicity and Clonezilla
- CIA of the company's data
- Networking services, TCP/IP, IP cameras, automatation.
- Raspberry Pi, microcomputing
- DDBB creation, tables add users and make consults on dbb

#### IT Technician internship

Fedeto Formación

April 2018 - June 2018 (3 months)

- Windows Server 2010-2012 Active Directory
- Unattended software installation
- IT Support N1 and N2
- Web with Wordpress
- Backups
- Maintenance, installation and repair of equipment. Hardware

#### **SKILLS**

- Good communication
- Problem solving
- Cybersecurity: ISO 27001 and use of tools.
- · Agility with results
- More than 5 years of experience with Linux

- in linkedin.com/in/franciscoolivares-martin-165b7b235/
- franciscolivares@protonmail.com
- <u>+34 651 563 210</u>
- fr4nsys.github.io
- github.com/fr4nsys

### **FORMACIÓN**

#### NetIQ Certified Partner Sales Specialist

Micro Focus 2023

# IM&G-Unified Endpoint Management Certified Presales Engineer (MFCPE)

Micro Focus 2023

#### **Ethical Hacking Essentials (EHE)**

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

#### <u>Digital Forensics Essentials</u> (DFE)

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

### Network Defense Essentials

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

# Practical Linux for Security Professionals

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

#### <u>Crash Course on Python de</u> <u>Google</u>

Coursera 2022

# Professional Certificate in IT Security

Fedeto Formación 2022

- Ciberseguridad
- Linux. Audit
- Snort, Wireshark, Nessus
- Metasploit Apache, Nginx
- VMware, Virtualbox
- Elastic Security, Splunk

### Google IT Support Certificate

Coursera 2022

### **AWS S3 Basics**

Coursera 2022

## Microcomputer Systems and Networks

I.E.S. Valdehierro 2018



- · Spanish: native
- English: B2 level













